libraries are like contracts except
库就像合同，除了没有存储空间，这意味着
there's no storage so that means that
you can't declare any state variables
您不能在库中声明任何状态变量，也不能
inside the library and also you can't
send any ETL to a library the benefits
将任何ETL发送到库使用库的好处是它可以帮助您
of using a library is that it helps you
keep your code try which stands for
保持您的代码尝试代表的意思，不要重复自己
don't repeat yourself in other words
you'll be able to reuse the code from
您将能够重用库中的代码
the library
and remove duplicate code one way this
并删除重复代码的一种方法是因为库允许
is achieved is because libraries allow
you to add functionality to the types so
您可以向这些类型添加功能，例如，假设您有一个
for example let's say that you have a
variable of type view and by using the
类型视图的变量，并通过使用库可以将联合国类型增强为
library the UN type can be enhanced to
have extra functionalities so that
具有额外的功能，这样您就可以执行以下操作
you'll be able to do something like this
call the function from the library on
从库中的变量X上调用函数的另一个好处是
the variable X the other benefit of
using the library is that it can't say
使用该库是它不能说喘着粗气，而这样做的方式是
gasps and the way this is done is that
you will first deploy the library and if
您将首先部署库，并且如果您有要使用的合同
you have a contract that is going to use
this library then you will first link
该库，那么您将首先将合同链接到以下库
the contract to the library that is
already deployed and this is done during
已经部署，并且在合同编制过程中完成，然后您
compilation of the contract and then you
will deploy the contract if you have
如果您有另一个要部署的合同，则将部署该合同
another contract that you want to deploy
that also uses this library then you
也会使用该库，那么您将再次重复相同的过程，
will repeat the same process again and
by doing so notice that I only deployed
通过这样做，请注意，我只部署了想要的库，而不是部署了它
the library want instead of deploying it
multiple times for each contact that
使用该库的每个联系人多次访问，这就是使用方式
uses the library and that's how using
the library can save gas
如果图书馆只有内部图书馆，图书馆现在可以节省汽油
now if the library has only internal
functions then the library will be
函数，然后将库嵌入到正在使用的合同中
embedded into the contract that is using
the library this means that when a
该库意味着在编译合同时，所有
contract is being compiled all of the
code inside the library will be put
库中的代码将放在合同中，所以我要显示
inside the contract so I'm gonna show
you how to write and use a library using
您将通过两个示例来说明如何编写和使用一个库，该库可以防止
two examples a library that prevents
hearing overflows and the library that
听觉上溢和图书馆，这将使您删除政府
will allow you to delete the government
from array without any gaps what do I
从阵列中没有任何间隙，我所说的坚固性是什么意思，我们需要
mean by this well in solidity we need to
veto element from array it does not
数组中的否决元素不会缩小数组，因此该库将
shrink the array so this library will
allow us
当我们的元素是
to shrink an array when our element is
deleted to define a library you first
删除以定义一个库，您首先输入库，然后我将其命名为
type library and I'll name this library
safe math and for this example we'll
安全的数学，在此示例中，我们将编写一个函数来防止您
write a function that will prevent you
and overflow when two units are added so
当添加两个单位时会溢出，所以我会将此功能命名为“坏”，这是
I'll name this function bad and it's
gonna take in to EWTN's this function
将加入EWTN的职能部门将是内部同行，
will be internal peer and it's gonna
return the sum of the two inputs we will
返回两个输入的总和，我们将首先将两个输入相加并检查
first add the two inputs and to check
that there was no overflow all we have
没有溢出，我们要做的就是确保总和更大
to do is make sure that sum is greater
than the points and if it is we turn
比点，如果是的话，我们将其打开并使用此安全数学
this on and to use this safe math
library inside this contract you type
您在合同中键入的库，其后使用
using followed by the name of the
library that you're on use so in this
您正在使用的库，因此在这种情况下，我们将采用安全的数学方法，并且我们希望
case we'll be safe math and we want to
extend the Union type so here we say for
扩展Union类型，所以我们在这里为您说，这行代码是什么
you and so what does this line of code
exactly mean well in general using a for
确切地讲，通常情况下，对于B使用a表示从a附加功能
B means attach functions from by very a
to type B so this kind of code means to
类型B，所以这种代码意味着将函数从安全路径附加到类型
attach functions from safe path to type
you int and if you have a variable of
您为int，并且如果您具有类型的变量，则可以使用
type of you and you'll be able to use
the function inside the safe math
像这样的安全数学库中的函数请注意
library like this here notice that were
only passing one parameter to the add
尽管该函数仅将一个参数传递给add函数
function although the function that
takes in two parameters this is because
接受两个参数，这是因为坚固性隐式地传递了第一个
solidity is implicitly passing the first
parameter but if you want to explicitly
参数，但如果要显式传递第一个参数，则可以执行此操作
pass the first parameter you can do it
like this so these are the two ways of
像这样，这是使用库和使用库的两种方式
using a library and to use the library
like the first way you'll have to
像第一种方法那样，您必须通过这条线来增强自己
enhance that you in tight with this line
of code using safe math for you and next
使用安全数学的代码示例，接下来让我们编写一个函数进行实际测试
let's write a function to actually test
this add function I'll name it test add
这个添加函数，我将其命名为test add，它将把您带入的工具
it's going to take in the tool you into
it and it's going to return the sum of
它会返回两个输入的总和，所以在函数内部
the two inputs so inside the function
will return X
将返回X的原因，并测试该行代码
why and to test that this line of code
will fail if there is a overflow we will
如果有溢出将失败，我们将通过在
call this function by adding max you in
to some other number which would cause
到其他一些会导致溢出的数字，这一行代码应该
an overflow and this line of code should
fail here are deployed the test safe
失败这里部署了测试安全数学合约，我们称之为测试
math contract and let's call the test
add function and check that this
添加功能并检查此功能是否正常工作，以便在我添加一个功能时
function is working so when I add one
and two I get three back and cause
和两个我得到三个回来，并导致溢出，我要添加最大hewent
overflow I'm gonna add max hewent
and one and call test add function and
然后调用test add函数，正如您在此处看到的，该函数失败了
as you can see here the function failed
so that was an example of using safe
因此，这是现在在实际编写算术语言时使用安全数学的一个示例
math now when you're actually writing a
smart contract you'll want to use open
智能合约，您将要使用已经使用过的开源库
source library that's already been
tested and used by many people and
经过许多人测试和使用，我个人将使用安全数学
personally I'll use the safe math
library from opens up and contracts
图书馆开放，接下来很多合同我要给你看
quite a lot next I'm gonna show you an
example of a library devil allow us to
库恶魔的示例允许我们从数组中删除元素，而无需任何操作
remove an element from array without any
depths normally when you delete the
通常，当您从数组实体中删除元素时，深度不会
element from array solidity will not
remove the element instead it will set
删除该元素，而是将DVD元素设置为其默认值，因此
the DVD element to its default value so
for an array of youant it was set the
对于youant数组，将其值设置为0，现在的技巧实际上是
value to 0 now the trick to actually
remove the element is to take the last
删除元素是将数组中的最后一个元素复制到
element in the array copy it over to the
place that is going to be deleted and
将要删除的位置，然后删除最后一个元素，因此我们将
then remove the last element so we'll do
exactly that name our function remove
确切地说，我们的函数名称删除，它将进入我们的int数组
it's gonna take in our array of you int
the arraignment that we're gonna be
我们将要删除的元素的提要将是您的
removing elements from will be your
state variables so we will declare
状态变量，所以我们将声明存储，第二个输入将是
storage and the second input will be the
index of the element to remove and for
要删除的元素的索引，在此示例中，我们将声明
this example we will declare the
function as public this means that this
作为公共功能，这意味着该库
library
we'll have to be deployed and then
我们必须先进行部署，然后链接其他合同才能使用它
linked for other contracts to use it
first we'll copy over the last element
首先，我们将数组的最后一个元素复制到
of the array into the position that is
going to be removed afterwards we remove
接下来将要删除的元素将被删除，接下来让我们编写一个
the last element next let's write a
contract to actually use this library
合同首先要实际使用该库，我将声明一个U数组
first I'm going to declare an array of U
and a state variable next we'll add the
接下来是一个状态变量，我们将将该库的功能添加到联合国
functionality of this library to the UN
array by writing using array for you int
通过为您的int数组使用array编写array，所以现在该合同将是
array so now in this contract will be
able to do something like this and call
能够做这样的事情，并调用数组中定义的remove函数
the remove function defined in the array
library next that's right your function
接下来的库是正确的，您可以将一些元素放入数组并
to put some elements into the array and
then remove some elements so you'll run
然后删除一些元素，这样您将运行一次for循环三遍，然后放入
a for loop for three times and then put
some numbers into the array so after the
一些数字放入数组，因此在for循环完成后，您将获得一个数组
for loop completes you'll have an array
of zero one and two and then we'll
零一和二，然后我们将删除索引一的元素，因此在这里
remove the element at index one so here
we're gonna remove one when we remove
我们将在索引1处删除元素时将其删除
the element at index one it's going to
copy the last element so index one will
复制最后一个元素，使索引1现在变为V 2，然后弹出最后一个
now V 2 and then it's gonna pop the last
element so after the function remove
元素，因此在函数删除完成后，您将剩下0，然后
completes you'll be left with 0 and then
2 and to check that that is the case
2并检查是否是这种情况将断言数组的长度
will assert that the length of the array
is equal to two first element in the
等于数组中的两个第一个元素等于零，第二个元素
array is so equal to zero and the second
element is equal to two what I call test
元素等于两个我称之为测试数组删除的元素，您可以在此处看到
array remove you can see here that the
transaction passed which means that it
交易通过了，这意味着它通过了我们的测试，因此这是一个
passed our test over here so that was a
demo of how to use a library
演示如何使用库，因此使用a4v语法进行总结
so in summary using the a4v syntax
you'll be able to add functions of
您将能够将库a的功能添加到
library a to
be the code of the library will be
是库的代码将被嵌入到正在使用的联系人中
embedded into the contact that is using
the library if all of the library
库，如果所有库函数都是内部函数，这将是
functions are internal and this will be
done when you compile the contract on
另一方面，当您通过某些功能编写合同时完成
the other hand if some by very functions
are either public or external then
是公共的还是外部的，那么您必须首先部署该库
you'll have to deploy the library first
and then link it with the contract that
然后将其与使用该库的合同链接，然后再进行部署
is using the library before deploying
the contract and by linking a contract
合同，并将合同链接到图书馆，您将可以节省汽油
to a library you'll be able to save gas
but since this feature isn't available
但由于无法在混音中使用此功能，因此无法向您展示
in remix I wasn't able to show you a
demo of this thanks for watching this
演示此视频感谢您观看本视频并祝您周末愉快
video and have a good weekend